Patrick A. Levell

email palevell@gmx.com • web palevell.github.io

Profile:

Results-driven Systems Analyst / Developer, Business Analyst, and Bitcoin enthusiast with broad-based experience in enhancing system functionality and end-user productivity. Accomplished professional who has earned a reputation for consistently meeting and exceeding aggressive objectives. Effective communicator possessing excellent interpersonal and relationship-building skills.

Computer Skills:

| System Software | Applications | Development Tools | |
|--|---------------------------|--|--|
| Oracle EnterpriseOne / JD Edwards OneWorld Xe | Libre Office, Open Office | PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite | |
| MS IIS/SharePoint | MS Office | SQL Server 2005/2008 (SSAS, SSIS, SSRS) | |
| Windows XP/2008 | MS Publisher | Visual Studio / Visual Basic | |
| Ubuntu Linux | Twitter API / Tweepy | PyCharm | |
| macOS & iOS | WordPress | Rational Rose UML | |

Professional Experience

Programmer / Analyst:

- Using JDEdwards EnterpriseOne ERP forms and reports in combination with VB.Net and SQL Reporting Services in delivering optimized business solutions for National Accounts, Sales & Marketing, Warranty Services, and the Raymond dealer network
- Developing, designing, implementing, testing and maintaining the iWarehouseTM Fleet Optimization System, Raymond's first commercial software offering
- Working closely with executives, consultants, customers, suppliers, and end-users to define and refine requirements for Raymond's IT infrastructure
- Monitoring and troubleshooting issues in JDEdwards, data warehouse, and iWarehouse
- Developing strategy for streamlining operations by integrating business processes
- Supervising consultants and junior programmers working on a variety of projects

Computer Systems Analyst / Developer:

- Designing, developing, implementing, testing, and maintaining custom applications and reports in JDEdwards OneWorld ERP/MRP for Engineering, EMS/QMS, and other business systems
- Developing specialized reports & applications with JDEdwards, SQL queries, Excel, Access and VB/VB.Net/SQL Server
- Working closely with end users in defining and "fine tuning" requirements & creating documentation
- Training and supporting JD Edwards users in Finance, MRP, Sales, Purchasing, and Inventory modules

Freelance Programmer / Webmaster / Database Administrator:

- Mentoring bloggers, entrepreneurs, and Bitcoin startups in building and maintaining their online presence
- Performing as technical liason for clients with advertisers
- · Administering customer databases
- Migrating web-sites to new servers

Related Volunteer Work

Community Manager:

People's Party of Canada Gatineau, Quebec (2019)

- Designing, developing, implementing, testing, and maintaining custom Twitter client
- Builiding a community for PPC candidates, volunteers, supporters, and critics
- Participating in "hashtag campaigns" with the following objectives:
 - to assist Maxime Bernier being invited to the national Leaders' Debates
 - to draw attention to the PPC platform
- Co-ordinating Twitter support teams for PPC candidates
- · Developing specialized reports for Twitter users

Director of Communications:

Electoral District Association

People's Party of Canada London, Ontario (2019)

- Building and managing social media presence on Facebook for local candidates
- Promoting events for local EDAs and Maxime Bernier
- Promoting fund-raising and merchandise pages

Employers

| Sole Proprietorship | London, Ontario | 2012 to Present |
|---------------------------|--------------------------|-----------------|
| The Raymond Corporation | Greene, New York | 2007 to 2012 |
| NUCOR Vulcraft – Florence | Florence, South Carolina | 1997 to 2007 |

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems DeVry University, Chicago, Illinois Cumulative GPA 3.62 (Honours)

Integrated ERP Project Highlights

Custom applications with components in multiple environments, including Oracle EnterpriseOne, JD Edwards OneWorld Xe, and SQL Server, as follows:

iWarehouse A web application for fleet management and optimization; modules include the following:

Gateway:

ilmpact: impact monitoring (asset protection) iMetrics: vehicle and operator utilization iVerify: operator checklist monitoring

iBattery: battery utilization

Capital

An intranet application to automate the capital appropriations request process, replacing the

Appropriations paper-based process

Request:

Exclusively ERP Project Highlights

Custom extensions or modifications on JD Edwards OneWorld Xe include the following:

Job Master **Inquiry:**

A management tool in JD Edwards, summarizing customer account and project information in credit, sales, finance, engineering, and manufacturing systems, improving documentation and communication between departments; Created a user manual and 25-minute training video for this application using Snaglt, MS Publisher, and MS PowerPoint

Production

Fixed sales, purchasing, manufacturing, delivery date issues; linked to Job Master Inquiry and Scheduler: Drafting Input; resulting in fewer problems between Sales and Drafting Completed, Not

Shipped (CNS) - the Finished Goods report - every nut & bolt in the plant is processed by this custom JD Edwards report—a critical piece of Vulcraft's month-end closing procedures; the Controller was using five other reports to get this information until CNS was fixed; month-end closing time was reduced by at least 20%; this report became an integral part of testing system

changes in JD Edwards

Material Resource Troubleshooting, modifying, and performance-enhancing on this suite of batch applications, to reconcile sales, purchasing, manufacturing, and shipping dates, and reduce execution time & system resource requirements, as this is a resource hog

(MRP):

Planning

The "Havens" A custom management report in JD Edwards, providing in-depth credit analysis of large and/or

problematic customer accounts, with two sections—one for the customer, and one for top-level Report:

management

180-Day

A custom financial report in JD Edwards for calculating customer credit scores, based on their

Weighted last six months of credit history

Average:

Over 40 Days: A custom financial report in JD Edwards for identifying overdue accounts

Deck A custom JD Edwards financial (MRP) report for the Controller and Purchasing Agent, detailing

current and projected raw material requirements Inventory:

Fab Schedule: The weekly production schedule from which most office activity stems; two specialized

versions of this report created for Drafting and Shop Order; ties in to Manufacturing, Customer

Service, Job Master, Drafting, and Shop Order Inquiry screens

Added additional fields for tracking approval drawings, and signaling Production Scheduler **Drafting Inquiry:**

whether drawings are in-process, out for approval, or back from approval; linked to the Job Master Inquiry and Shop Order Inquiry screens; resulting in providing Production Scheduler

with up-to-the minute information for scheduling purposes

Shop Order Added additional fields for tracking bills of materials (aka. shop orders) through the engineering

Inquiry: design program (outside of JD Edwards); linked to Job Master Inquiry and Drafting Inquiry screens; resulting in much improved traceability and fewer interruptions in Data Entry from

Drafting and Shop Order, asking for information

A management tool in JD Edwards combining bill of lading, sales, and shipping data for much Shipping

Inquiry: improved reachability

A key custom JDE financial report used for invoicing, reported tons & dollars Daily

Shipments:

SO - SF A custom JDE application for comparing what was sold to what was built & shipped; used

Compare: primarily on large jobs to show the dollar amount left to be invoiced

Re-price A custom JDE application for re-pricing jobs, typically used when design requirements change

Program:

Custom Application Highlights

Custom development using MS Excel/Access/.Net include the following:

Internal Audit A custom MS Access database application for managing internal audits of quality and

Manager: environmental management systems; generates checklists, audit questions, and audit reports

Inventory A custom MS Excel spreadsheet application to analyze supplier promised & actual delivery dates using data from inventory and cost of quality spreadsheets; results delivered using

System: charts, graphs, and pivot tables

NUVU BoM A stand-alone application using VB.Net & SQL queries to transfer XML data from NUVU bills of

Transfer: materials to the engineering design program, effectively getting NUVU (AutoCAD) to talk to the design program, written in FORTRAN, and still thinks it is running on punch cards; complete

with installer and auto-update feature for local and satellite sales offices

Shipping This was a tool to move the current delivery dispatches ("route-out") procedures from

Route-out paper-based to electronic; prototyped in MS Access and later integrated into J.D. Edwards **Prototype:**

NUVU Installer: A collection of shell scripts, HTML, and VB.Net programs to install NUVU on AutoCAD

workstations, including network security and administrative shares. All the users had to do to

install NUVU was click on a single web-link

Joist Input A front-end to the engineering design program, written in VB5 utilizing a SQL Server database

Program: instead of the old flat-files; object model created using Rational Rose; prototyping done in MS

Access

Special Projects

- Created a Twitter bot help build a social media presence for a new political party in Canada
- Recovered stolen Internet domain name for a Colorado-based real estate brokerage firm; the investigation tracked the domain records down in Australia, and the owner in Spain; assistance was obtained from the International Trade Administration at the US Department of Commerce
- Served as Senior Lead Internal Auditor for six years. Led the team to make the transition from ISO 9001:1994 to ISO 9001:2000, which included leading the team that re-wrote the quality manual, and moving the quality manual from paper-based to an interactive on-line system, using MS Internet Information Server (IIS), SharePoint, and FrontPage
- Routinely served as corporate liaison with outside auditors of both our quality and environmental management systems

Cryptocurrency Project Highlights

- Owned & operated a Bitcoin mining farm, starting with two (2) FPGA miners, expanded to six (6) first-generation ASIC miners and a second-generation ASIC miner
- First-ever web-scraper to collect account information from the GBBG|BitBillions 1 web-site